Guide to the Reeve Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Reeve family papers
1766-1813
MS 686
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
Correspondence of Tapping Reeve, jurist, author, and teacher of law, and of his wife, Sarah Burr Reeve, sister of Aaron Burr (1756-1836). Correspondents include Joel Barlow, Aaron Burr, Peter Colt, Jonathan Edwards, Pierpont Edwards, Timothy Edwards, and John Cotton Smith. The letters relate to both family and business affairs.
Reeve family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Formerly a part of the Annie Burr Jennings Memorial Collection.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Sarah Burr Reeve. II. Tapping Reeve.
Related Materials
For additional related material, please see the Burr Family Collection (MS 303), of which these papers were once a part.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist almost entirely of correspondence, filed alphabetically under the name of the correspondent. The correspondence between Sarah and Tapping Reeve is filed under the recipient.
Biographical / Historical
The Reeve Family Papers consist of the papers of Sarah (Burr) Reeve and Tapping Reeve.
Sarah (Burr) Reeve, or "Sally," was born in 1754 at Newark, New Jersey. She was the daughter of Aaron Burr (1716-1757), scholar, theologian, and second president of the College of New Jersey (Princeton) and of Esther (Edwards) Burr, daughter of Jonathan Edwards, the New England divine. Her brother was Aaron Burr (1756-1836), soldier, politician, and third vice-president of the United States. After the death of their parents, both she and her brother were tutored for a time by Tapping Reeve. She subsequently married Mr. Reeve and had one son by him, Aaron Burr Reeve (1780-1809). Sarah (Burr) Reeve died in 1787.
Tapping Reeve, jurist, teacher of law, and author of legal books, was born in 1744 at Brookhaven, Long Island, N.Y., the son of Abner Reeve, a Presbyterian clergyman. After graduating from the College of New Jersey in 1763 he spent some time teaching and as a tutor. In 1771 he moved to Connecticut to study law with Judge Root in Hartford. In 1784 he founded the Litchfield Law School, the earliest and for many years the most important in the country. In 1798 Reeve was appointed a judge of the Superior Court of Connecticut and in 1814 he was made chief justice of the Supreme Court of Errors. Tapping Reeve died in 1823.
Families; Law; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; Lawyers; Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836; Colt, Peter, 1744-1824; Edwards, Jonathan, 1745-1801; Edwards, Pierpont, 1750-1826; Edwards, Timothy, 1738-1813; Lyman, Polly; Ogden, Mary, 1754-1791; Reeve, Sally Burr, 1754-1797; Reeve, Tapping, 1744-1823; Smith, John Cotton, 1765-1845; Burr family; Reeve family; Litchfield Law School
- Sarah Burr Reeve: Correspondence, Series I
  - Burr, Aaron (1756-1836), 1773-1780 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Burr, Eunice (Dennie) [Mrs. Thaddeus Burr] (1729-1805), 1773-1774, 1780 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Burr, Theodosia (Prevost) (?-1794), [1780], 1782, [1783] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edwards, Jonathan (1745-1801), 1770 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edwards, Pierpont (1750-1826), 1771 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edwards, Timothy (1738-1813), 1770-1772 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Gill, Sarah (Prince) [Mrs. Moses Gill], 1766, 1767, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Howard, Elizabeth (Clarke) Mayhew, 1771, 1774 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hunt, Eunice (Edwards) Pollock, 1778 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lyman, Polly, 1769, 1770, 1772, 1777 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ogden, Mary (1754-1791), 1769 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Parsons, Sarah, 1770 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reeve, Tapping, 1769, 1772-1773 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Wainwright, Elizabeth (Mayhew), 1780 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cap once belonging to Sarah (Burr) Reeve (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Tapping Reeve: Correspondence, Series II
  - Barlow, Joel, 1781 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Burr, Aaron (1756-1836), 1775, [1776], 1780, 1783, 1785, 1813, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Burr, Annabelle (Sheldon) Reeve (1789-1849), 1812 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Burr, Thaddeus (1735-1799), 1775, 1777, 1783, 1787, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Burr, Theodosia (Prevost), 1789, [1780], [1786] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Colt, Peter, 1773 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Edwards, Jonathan, Jr. (1745-1801), 1775 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Edwards, Timothy (1738-1813), 1775 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reeve, Aaron Burr (1780-1809), 1802, 1807 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reeve, Abner, 1778 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reeve, Elizabeth (1773-1842), [1801] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Reeve, Sarah (Burr) (1754-1797), 1772 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Smith, John Cotton, 1802 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Starr, Samuel, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 11)